Guide to the Department of Animal Science records,1949-1990.
Department of Animal Science records, 1949-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Department of Animal Science records, 1949-1990.
21-14-2565
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.Department of Animal Science.
3.2 cubic ft.
Publications, Reports, Research Materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records pertaining to research and extension, including the New York State Fair, particularly with sheep, swine, and goats, 1949-1973.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
C. R. Henderson, for many years a professor in the Department of Animal Science, was world-renowned in the area of animal breeding.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records pertaining to research and extension, including the New York State Fair, particularly with sheep, swine, and goats, 1949-1973.
Also, two video cassettes of "The Legacy of C. R. Henderson," from the American Dairy Science Association Symposium, June 1990, and radio talks (1949-1955) given by faculty over the Rural Radio Network.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; Henderson, C. R.(Charles R.); American Dairy Science Association.
Subjects:
Animal industry.; Sheep.; Swine.; Goats.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- New York State Exposition, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
- Autopsies-Disease-Sheep, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Farm Flock Records-Empire Shepherd's Club I, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Farm Flock Records-Empire Shepherd's Club II, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Farm Flock Records-Empire Shepherd's Club, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Farm Flock Records, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Farm Flock Summaries-Empire Shepherd's Club, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Livestock & Agent Training Schools Extension, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Publications-Articles I, 1945-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Publications-Articles II, 1945-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Publications From The Laboratory of Animal Breeding and Artificial Insemination (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Scabies-Sheep Health & Disease (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Shearing Contest & Equipment Shearing Schools (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sheepmen's Short Course, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Specialist's Meeting-Empire Shepherd's Club, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Eastern Seaboard Sheep Council, 1957-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- New York State Sheep Improvement Project Cooperative, Inc., 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4-9)
- American Wool Council, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- American Dairy Goat Association, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- New York State Exposition, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- NYS Exposition-"Wool Queen" and "Make it yourself Contest," Paid Expenditures, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- New York State Fair-Swine, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- New York State Fair-Sheep and Goats, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- New York State Fat Stock Show and Sale, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- New York Meat Animal Show and Sale-Annuals, 1961-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Posters, Releases and Articles, 1955-1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Minutes, Bylaws-Western NY Fat Stock Show & Sale, NY Meat Animal Show $ Sale, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Address of Buyers Who Didn't Buy in 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Show Exhibiters, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Film Negatives-Stock Sales, 1868-1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Data on Sale Buyers, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Data on Sale Buyers, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Data on Sale Buyers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Sale Supporters, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Assiciation Specials, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Association Specials, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Association Specials, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Carcass Show, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- First Butter Factory in the U. S., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Judges, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Judges, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- New York State Fair, 1949-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11-24)
- Petition for Barn, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Premium Book, 1957, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
- Rural Radio Network Talks, 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
- History of the Department of Animal Science- Prepared By J.M. Elliot, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 2 panoramic photos, 1941, 1947 (Folder 1)
  Including: American Dairy Science Association, Meeting, University of Vermont, Burlington, June 23-26, 1941
  American Dairy Science Association, Ontario Agriculture College, Guelph, June 24-26th, 1947
- The Legacy of C. R. Henderson," from the American Dairy Science Association Symposium, June 1990; V-57, V-58